♪ It seems today
that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies
and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man
who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a...
Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
Oh, Stewie,
how exciting!
Your first visit to
a real fire station!
Yeah, you kids always loved your
first trip to the fire station.
You remember when we took Meg?
Welcome to the Quahog
Fire Department, folks.
I'm Captain Beckman.
Let me know if you
have any questions
that I can
answer for you.
JOE:
What's up, nerds?
You waiting for some guy to
fall asleep with a cigarette?
Lazy fire turds!
Have another donut, pig!
We got guns! You got hoses!
See you on the softball field!
Over here is our kitchen,
where we make all our meals.
And upstairs
is where we sleep.
What about your
wives and families?
Sometimes we don't see them
for long periods of time.
Well, that sounds
awfully lonely.
Like being an NBA player
on the road.
Baby, I miss my wife so much.
Thanks for understanding
that we can't do anything.
I just want to cuddle.
Oh, you're so sweet.
I'm just doing
what a man should do.
Respecting the sacred
institution of marriage.
And now, straight to sleep.
ANNOUNCER: This message brought
to you by the NBA.
Let's all pretend this happens.
Hey, Chris, you think it's safe
to drink from a fire hose?
Why not, Dad?
It's just water.
All right, well, turn it on.
I'm very thirsty.
Nice job, Chris.
You got my shirt wet.
Now, few people realize
that until 1928
there were no hoses,
and you actually had to fight
fires with your bare hands.
I will now give
a demonstration.
(grunts)
Whoa, scrappy little blaze, huh?
Oh, my God,
the fire's got a gun!
What the (bleep) was that?
(making driving noises)
Come on, Stewie.
We're going.
Just a moment, Brian.
I'm pretending
I'm a fireman.
I love playing pretend.
My name's Peter
and I work in the brewery.
Now I'm gonna put on my pants
and go talk
to my coworkers at...
These pants have
stool in them.
Well, I hope everyone had a fun
afternoon at the firehouse.
I sure did, Mom!
I can't wait for the
next family outing!
Aw, thanks, Mike.
I hate fire stations.
(man's voice): No problem, man.
(sniffing)
Is that alcohol
on your breath?
Yeah, maybe.
You're playing this
too fast and loose, Mike!
Ooh, ooh, is
that the mail?
Yeah.
Is there anything in there for me?
I want to see if
there's a response
to all those fan letters
I've been writing.
PETER:
Dear Cary Elwes,
I have been meaning to
contact you for some time.
I have never been able to
figure out if you are famous.
You were a big deal
in one thing,
but you were wearing
a mask for most of it.
Do you consider your
career a disappointment?
Or rather, did you exceed
your own expectations?
Yours truly, Peter Griffin.
P.S. You were in
Robin Hood: Men in Tights.
Did you know that?
Hey, there's something here
from the Nielsen Company.
"Dear Griffin family,
"You have been specially
selected from amongst millions
"of American households
to be a Nielsen family,
"and as such, to have your
TV viewing habits monitored
in order to measure
television ratings."
Oh, kids, this came
all the way from Delaware.
What does all
that mean?
Well, Meg, it sounds like
they want us to be part of
a select group of people that
helps determine what's on TV.
We're gonna be a Nielsen family?
That's awesome!
(somber, sad music plays)
I think... uh...
I think that's
the wrong music.
(victorious fanfare plays)
There you go.
Now, this Nielsen box will keep
track of everything you watch,
which helps us generalize
the viewing habits
of millions of Americans.
Ah, yes.
And what was that beginning,
middle and end part again?
Um...
this Nielsen box will keep track
of everything you watch,
which helps us generalize
the viewing habits
of millions of Americans.
Is there any way you can
describe that to me
using colorful puppets
of some sort?
The Nielsen box will monitor
your viewing habits!
(scratchy laugh)
I don't like the left puppet.
His chin is scary.
Well, thanks
for your cooperation.
If you have any questions,
please call me.
And welcome
to the Nielsen family.
Thank you very much.
Well, isn't this exciting.
I know, I can't believe
we're a Nielsen family!
I never get picked
for anything.
(people screaming)
All right, everyone.
Time to do
our Nielsen duty.
So, what are we gonna watch?
Boobs!
Project Runway!
The Good Wife!
That black version of our show!
You know, guys, this
is a real opportunity
to promote quality
programming.
I think we should
watch PBS.
Yeah, you're real
passionate about PBS.
You donated once five years ago
and they sent you a mug.
And now the mug's so old
that the "P" has been worn off
so it just says "B.S."
It's libtards like you that are
screwing up our country.
(knock at door)
Tom Tucker?
What are you doing here?
Well, I heard you're
the new Nielsen family.
Just hoping you plan to watch
the Channel Five News.
I don't know.
I've missed so many.
It's gonna take me
forever to catch up.
Well, we'd sure love
to have you as a viewer.
Is there anything we can do
to make the news
more appealing to you?
Maybe.
I guess you could
lose the moustache.
Lose my moustache?
Well, gosh, I...
I don't know.
My birthmark
makes it kind of tough.
Always caused me problems
at my old job.
And that'll do it for us here
at Channel 12 News.
Make sure you turn
those clocks ahead.
Good night, St. Louis.
Yeah, I don't know,
I was never that crazy
about the moustache.
Well, I suppose I could lose it
and just use more makeup.
Yeah, that'd be cool.
And maybe a festive hat would
make things more festive.
All right, this is good.
Any other suggestions?
Yeah, can you end each show
by trying to pull-start
a very cold chain saw?
Well, that shouldn't
be a problem.
All right, thank you
for being so candid.
Hey, thanks for listening.
I know how hard it is
to take criticism.
Hey, nice boots, Griffin.
They sell men's shoes
where you got those?
PETER: You made a commitment
to these boots, Peter.
These boots are the new you,
and no one will shake that.
Yee-haw, ride 'em, cowgirl!
PETER: Okay, you can take
the boots off at lunch.
Go to the gym.
Have a workout.
Come back in your sneakers.
If anyone asks, you forgot
the boots in your locker.
Just make it to lunch.
Those boots are
made for walkin'.
Up to guys' butts.
(laughing)
Hey, fellas.
Hey.
TOM TUCKER:
Good evening, Quahog.
Tonight, Channel Five
mourns the loss
of a dear colleague.
My moustache.
And as per the wishes
of my moustache,
his ashes were sprinkled
off the coast of Acapulco
where he was born.
Well, that'll do it for us here.
Thanks for watching
Channel Five,
the most trusted name in news.
Ah, crap.
Oh, come on.
Let's go, Tom.
Work, damn it!
What the hell?
What's going on
with the news?
This is terrible!
Yeah, has he lost his mind?
Well, I'll be damned.
If I knew he was gonna do
all that stuff I told him,
I would've told him
more stuff.
What?
Peter, you told him
to do this crap?
Yeah, he came to my house
when he found out
I was a Nielsen family,
asked what I wanted to see.
Hey, hey, you know
what would be cool?
If he did the news with
a family of prairie dogs,
and whenever he said
something sad,
they'd pop their heads up,
all concerned.
Peter, you sure that's
such a good idea?
People rely on the local news
to provide them with
several stories a year on how
saltwater taffy is made.
Yeah, if you're
a Nielsen family,
it seems like you
should maybe be
a little more thoughtful
with your choices.
What are you talking about?
I'm just having a little fun.
For God's sakes,
I've just been handed
the coolest freaking toy
on the planet.
Well, you know, except for
Hungry Hungry Alec Baldwins.
Hey, I'm not... I'm not
even touching the lever.
Chilling news
from Long Island Sound,
as a four-passenger prop plane
on its way to East Hampton
spun into the surf
off Montauk Point.
There were no survivors.
Oh, that's so great, I just
called him on the way home!
Peter, I'm not sure this
is entirely responsible.
I don't see what
the big deal is.
I was just trying
to make the show better.
Hell, I wish I could do it
with all the shows.
Yeah, well, you only have
one Nielsen box.
You don't have the clout
to affect national shows.
Damn it.
I guess that means
I'll never get to see
an episode of Superman
where Clark Kent and Lois Lane
finally get together.
Lois, I love you,
and I want there to be
no more secrets between us.
I am Superman.
Oh, my God.
The only thing that can
kill me is kryptonite.
Or latex.
Or lambskin.
What about polyurethane?
All that.
All that stuff.
(knock at door)
Hi, folks.
Just thought I'd stop by
and make sure your equipment
is working properly and see
if you have any questions.
Yeah, is something wrong
with our remote?
No matter how low
I turn the volume,
Aziz Ansari is always
shouting at me.
What did I do?
Thank you.
I think we're good.
Everything seems
to be going well.
Okay, great.
Well, I'm just gonna
change out the card
on your unit real quick
and I'll be on my way.
Well, we're all set.
Thanks for your time.
No, thank you, pal.
And hey, you've been
working hard.
Why don't you take the
rest of the day off?
Here's two tickets to Sandra
Bernhard's one-woman show.
Wow, thanks!
Yeah, and they're
great seats.
They're right in
the gap of her teeth.
Social media?
More like a social disease.
(audience laughs)
Ha! That's funny!
Peter, what the hell's
going on here?
Lois, we're no longer
one Nielsen family.
We're 100.
More boxes, more power.
And I got some ideas
to make TV better.
(phone rings)
Hello, Mad Men
production office.
Yeah, Peter Griffin here.
Could I speak with
Jon Hamm, please?
One moment.
(phone rings)
Hello?
Hello, Jon Hamm?
Peter Griffin,
Nielsen family.
Listen, did I catch
you at a good time,
or are you and the critics busy
sucking each other's butts?
Excuse me?
Look, your show
is really boring.
But don't worry,
I got some ideas
on how you
can jazz it up.
Listen, I don't need
your suggestions, pal.
I've been a big celebrity
for a year and a half now.
Okay, if that's
how you're gonna be.
We'll see how
this plays out.
Lois, we're not watching
Mad Men no more.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Look, I may have been
a little rash.
Our ratings
have dropped 50%.
Whatever suggestions
you have, I'll listen.
And so, gentlemen,
in baseball,
three strikes
and you're out.
But three Lucky Strikes...
and you're in.
Nice try, Don.
But I'm afraid
we're going to have
to take our business
elsewhere.
Oh? don't think so.
(playing Star Wars theme)
What the hell was that?
I'll tell you
what it was, Lois.
It was awesome.
And wait'll
you see Breaking Bad.
I don't know what it was,
but now it's on roller skates.
Hi, NBC,
this is Peter Griffin.
Listen, you guys
are doing a great job.
If anybody knows what America
wants in the '90s, it's NBC.
But I just have
one small request:
I like Dateline, but I really
hate waiting two hours
to find out who the killer is.
ANNOUNCER: Tonight on Dateline,
a woman murdered.
Was it her ex-boyfriend?
Yes, it was.
I knew it.
I knew it was the ex-boyfriend.
"Sleep tight, truck.
"Sleep tight, firefly.
"Sleep tight, chair.
Sleep tight, bird."
You see that, Peter?
You see the bird?
Bird.
Okay, we'll, uh,
pick up the rest tomorrow.
Uh, now, I'm just gonna vamp for
a while with some random noises.
Hee-hee!
Heya, heya, heya.
(grumbling, groaning)
Uh-heh, uh-heh...
(gibbering)
Okay, good night, Peter.
Good night, Dave.
LETTERMAN:
And, uh, here's Paul
to play you to sleep
with a lullaby.
PAUL (off-key):
♪ Hey, lullaby... ♪
♪ Oh, lullaby ♪
♪ Hey, you, lullaby... ♪
Stop, no, stop.
Stop.
I forgot, he's terrible.
TV ANNOUNCER: We now return to
Cops With Banana Guns.
Freeze!
Is that...
is that a banana?
Don't worry
about what it is.
I'm still a cop.
Whoa, hold on.
All-All right, just...
just take it easy.
This can go
a couple of ways.
What the hell
did Peter do to Cops?!
Bonnie!
Come push me out in a huff!
Peter, what is this show?
It's called Creeping Up
on the Kardashians.
See that guy with the
ponytail in the background?
He sneaks up and
scares the girls
while they're
starting businesses
or getting
their fat waxed.
(all scream)
What the hell?!
(crowd clamoring)
There they are!
That's the Nielsen family!
You ruined television!
Now it's just
a big, old, silly mess!
Oh, God! An angry mob!
I've got to swallow all my
valuables and get out of here!
Did you see the mob?
Did I see the mob?
Why else am I here?
(clamoring)
Oh, my God, Peter,
they're really angry!
Say something!
W-Wait.
What the hell's going on?
What do you mean,
I ruined television?
You put a real cougar
on Cougar Town,
and now that cougar's dead
because Courtney Cox ripped it
apart with her teeth and claws!
You turned Anderson Cooper 360
into Anderson Cooper 720!
He's turning around too much!
You converted The Biggest Loser
to the metric system!
Now it feels like
they're not losing enough!
Aw, the hell with you guys!
You're just jealous 'cause I get
to say what's on TV now!
I am a Nielsen god!
(cheering)
Sorry, y'all.
That's the first time
I ever throwed anything.
Well, if it isn't
Mr. Nielsen himself.
Nurse, who's the worst
doctor in this hospital?
You are,
Dr. Hartman.
Good.
Put Hartman on this bozo.
Hey, what can
I do for you?
Please, Doc, you got to
help me with this nasty gash.
What seems
to be the problem?
No, it's my husband.
Oh. Well, you've got a lot
of nerve coming in here
after what you
did to television.
Now, get out!
Please, Doctor,
you've got to help him.
You took an oath when
you went to medical school.
I took a lot of things when
I went to medical school.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to answer this.
Hello?
Ah, Hartman!
Hey, guys.
How you doing?
Not so good, Peter.
Yeah, me, either.
Thanks to you,
TV's a vast wasteland.
You know how
I know that phrase?
I read it in a book,
you monster!
Aw, come on, let me
make it up to you.
Let me buy you a beer.
No, that seat's taken.
Move along, Peter.
What are you
talking about?
You guys are my pals.
We used to be, Peter.
Now, scram.
Well, fine,
I'll sit at the bar.
Not at my bar, you won't.
Get out of here!
Geez, I can't
show my face anywhere.
I might as well be back
doing public radio.
This is Peter Griffin,
and you're listening
to Book Talk on WRNI.
Today we'll be discussing
Bret Easton Ellis's
popular work,
Less Than Zero, a tale
of privilege, detachment
and youthful alienation.
(taking a long, loud sip of tea)
But first,
a word from our sponsor,
Westin's Golden Soda Biscuits.
I'm enjoying one right now.
(crunches biscuit)
Mmm.
(sips, then crunches)
(sips tea, crunches biscuit)
Mmm.
(sips tea)
That concludes
today's session of Book Talk.
Tune in tomorrow when we will
look at John Kennedy Toole's
unheralded early work,
The Neon Bible.
Hey, what's wrong, Peter?
I miss my friends, Brian.
I mean, I was having fun
with those Nielsen boxes,
but what's the point
if I don't got Joe and
Quagmire to enjoy it with me?
I guess I shouldn't have
messed with television.
Well, it's not
exactly your fault.
The networks never should
have listened to you
in the first place.
This is exactly what
makes bad television:
pandering to the lowest
common denominator.
So what do I do, Brian?
Well, you still
have these boxes.
That means you still have the
power to influence television.
Maybe you can use that
power to help restore TV
to the way it was.
You're right, Brian.
Maybe if I watch
smart, quality shows,
that'll help get things back
to the way they were.
We can use these boxes
for good and...
What the hell?!
That's for adding another tree
to One Tree Hill!
Oh, my God, he destroyed
every last box!
Holy crap!
We're sunk now, Peter.
There goes your one chance to
get TV back to the way it was.
Wait a minute.
Maybe not, Brian.
I think I just got an idea.
Aah!
I got glass in my face!
Oh, crap.
Now I forgot what it was.
I got it!
Aah! Son of a bitch!
You know who I hate?
The troops.
Yeah, me, too.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
who are you?
I'm Peter Griffin.
I'm the guy
who ruined television,
and I'm the guy
who's gonna fix it.
Guys!
I broke television,
and now you have
to help me fix it!
Yah-ha!
Looks like this is one
we beat you to.
Gentlemen, I have
gathered you all here today
because you are the creators
of what television used to be
before I ruined it.
And we need to rebuild
television from the ground up.
So, I'm gonna need
all your best ideas.
J.J. Abrams, you take
wonder and complexity
and present it in a way that
no one can possibly understand.
Whaddaya got?!
I've got an alien
that goes back in time
and encounters a koala bear
in an Eastern European town.
Totally confused.
Do it!
Okay, now, we're gonna need
15 workplace comedies
where people talk
to the camera for some reason.
You, you, you and you-- go.
When Peter told me to make
a workplace comedy
where people talk
to the camera, I thought...
Not now!
I mean, go do a show!
Don't-don't do
that thing here.
Huh.
Wonder if I can
pull off one of those
"can you believe what
I have to put up with" looks
to the camera.
Okay, Mark Burnett, you did
Survivor and The Apprentice.
Can you give me a reality show
where people do horrible,
unforgiveable things
to each other
for embarrassingly
small sums of money?
I got some ideas.
Here's a nickel,
pull down your pants.
There's a show.
Yah-ha! Go!
All right, now,
who's gonna make a show
about horrible
New Jersey freaks?
You know what?
I don't care.
Just someone, do it!
Okay, Dick Wolf,
make the same Law and Order
six times.
Oh, and also,
could you marry Matt Weiner
'cause I want your name
to be Dick "Weener."
Okay, but can I go by
"Dick Wolf-Weener"?
Oh, my God, yes!
Yes! Yes!
Okay, Bravo people,
go find women fighting.
No, you know what,
just find women.
They'll end up fighting.
All right, everyone who's left,
make a talent show.
We are done.
Oh, Kelsey Grammer,
what are you still doing here?
I-I have nothing left
for you.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Ah. Then I shall take
my ease on the lanai.
I don't care
what you do now.
TV ANNOUNCER: We now return
to Mike and Molly.
Have you decided
what you'd like to order?
Yes, the chopped salad?
I'll have everything
except that.
(studio audience laughing)
(laughing)
That waiter's like, "What?!"
Well, you did it, Peter.
You got TV back to normal.
Yeah, guys,
I'm sorry for screwing up
all your favorite shows.
Ah, that's okay, Peter.
So, what do you say?
Are we pals again?
Ah, course we are.
You bet.
Well, let's drink
to having TV
back in the hands of people
who know what they're doing.
I think Zack and Cody
would be funnier
if they did the show
in their underpants.
Thank you for watching "Family Guy" on
www.FOX-fan.ru